Steps for Calculating a Performance Baseline
Hello, Mike Harry back with you again, where we’re looking at baselining.
Recall that we took our unit error rate divided by the opportunities.
Recognizing that an opportunity here, could be the number of defect categories,
could be the number of things that could go wrong, or it could be the number
of things that has to go right. And we messed up,
say .05 per unit, four things had to go right per unit.
Then that's our opportunity error rate.
Of course multiplying that by a million gives us our DPMO.
Now, taking to the fourth step, we take the DPMO,
and we simply enter into a table of Sigma values.
We look up the DPMO and we see the corresponding Sigma is 3.74.
In other words, a 3.74 Sigma capability
is equivalent to 12,500 defects per million opportunities.
So, it's a way to express it.
The 3.74 is our baseline capability per opportunity.
And it's really pretty much that simple. So, when we look at these different applications,
I could say this teller right here is 3.74 Sigma,
but yet another teller, perhaps right here might be 4.2 Sigma.
Or a teller in the background here could be Five Sigma.
So, that would beg the question,
why is this person's baseline significantly higher than this person's?
Well, we would investigate, find out the causes,
and then perhaps standardize on the superior process.
In short, you can't tell where you're going
and how far you've come, without the post in the ground.
That's where you've been. What you did. So, you got a baseline from which that benchmark
becomes your guiding light
of how much, and how far you've come, in your improvement effort.
So, that's the simplest case here of baselining.
In this instance, we baseline with discrete data, pass-fail data, good-bad.
We can also do the same thing, with a few different steps, for continuous data.
Based upon means and standard deviations, and the histograms and so on.
For whether it's in normal data, nonnormal data.
So, we can literally benchmark virtually anything.
We can lay down a baseline for all of the core operations within a business.
Baseline them, determine how much improvement has to occur
and then periodically measure our rate of improvement against the baseline.
Let me say that again. This allows us to set forth a rate of improvement.
So, if my baseline is 12,500 defects per million opportunities,
corresponding to 3.74 Sigma.
And I want to improve, say that the DPMO rate,
at 30% per year over the next five years.
I can then see the Sigma capability of where I'm going. Where I want to be.
In order to close that gap, that's where we go in, identify projects.
Black belt, green belt projects. Execute those projects to derive that rate of improvement.
So, with that thought in mind, that concludes our discussion on establishing baselines.